There are 12 of them.
12 stadiums built in the four corners of Europe.
Conceived by the most daring architects and built by thousands of workers and engineers.
12 gigantic arenas selected to host matches for a global event,
the 2020 European Football Championship.
...embark on a unique tour of Europe to discover the most beautiful stadiums on the continent.
In this episode,
The match will pit the Olympic Stadium in Rome, Italy against the San Mames Stadium in Bilbao, Spain.
On one hand,
a historic stadium.
A stadium built in barely two years and which,
to meet construction deadlines,
demanded revolutionary technologies.
For FIFA,
It was impossible to build this stadium in such a short time.
It was a true miracle.
On the other hand,
a stadium fully integrated into the city which has successfully met a major challenge.
To preserve the mythical atmosphere of the old San Mames stadium while modernizing it.
The atmosphere in the stadium is deafening.
The players feel it and it makes their hair stand on end.
Two stadiums that took the gamble of destroying everything in order to rebuild everything in record time.
Let's begin
our journey through Italy and its eternal city,
Rome.
Located in the west-central part of the peninsula,
crossed by the Tiber,
The Mediterranean capital is home to 3 million inhabitants.
A veritable open-air history book,
Rome oscillates between tradition and modernity.
Exceptional historical monuments stand alongside contemporary architectural works,
like the Foro Italico.
Built under Mussolini between 1927 and 1933,
This large sports complex houses remarkable remains adjacent to a large modern building.
the Olympic stadium.
Through this vast architectural complex,
The Italian despot wished to consolidate his power and promote his regime.
To reach the stadium,
You have to take a central artery 130 meters long.
Upon entering,
a gigantic marble obelisk,
37 meters high and weighing over 300 tons.
The Mussolini obelisk still sparks much controversy.
because the Mussolini-Dux inscription is still present.
The arrival of this monolith was epic.
It was transported by river on a barge before being carried in front of St. Peter's Basilica as if to pay homage to the Pope.
Then it was left on the ground on the central artery for several years.
In 1932,
the two architects,
Constantini and Piantonello,
have modified the base of the monolith, reminiscent of avant-garde architecture.
To install the monolith in its final position,
They used a lever system that allowed them to tilt the obelisk vertically.
On this central artery,
The floor is decorated with 5000 m2 of mosaic that celebrates sport.
22 marble blocks were erected on either side of the walkway.
The Italico forum,
designed by architect Enrico del Debbio,
is centered around the spherical fountain square.
It is from this fountain that the paths leading to the various sports facilities begin.
The Olympic stadium,
formerly known as the Cypress Stadium,
tennis courts,
The rugby pitch,
swimming pools,
basketball or volleyball courts,
the central walkway of the complex which runs through the Fascist male academy of physical education and Mussolini's private gymnasium.
Finally, to conclude,
the marble stadium,
dominated by 62 monumental statues of athletes.
The sculpted crown is the result of a competition in which artists from all over the country participated.
Each statue was paid for by a different municipality in Italy.
The Foro Italico is designed to host major international competitions.
And from the very beginning,
special attention is given to the Cypress Stadium.
It was built in 1927 by the architect Del Debbio and is located on the current site of the Olympic Stadium.
In 1937,
another architect,
Luigi Moretti,
resumes the project and adds two rings to the Cyprès stadium.
Although still under construction,
The enclosure has the makings of a monument worthy of being displayed to the world.
Mussolini's regime chose it to host Hitler's visit in 1938.
For the occasion,
The stadium is decorated with 24 towers topped with imperial eagles,
immediately dismantled after the event.
Construction of the stadium was then interrupted by the Second World War.
then resumed in 1950 to give rise to the stadium of one hundred thousand.
It was called the stadium of one hundred thousand because there were one hundred thousand spectators.
It was huge and many people were standing.
Major events have taken place in this stadium.
Regularly,
The 100,000 stadium is in the spotlight.
In 1960,
It hosts the Olympic Games,
then the European football championships,
but also the World Athletics Championships.
From 1987 onwards,
A major construction project will completely alter the morphology of the stadium.
In May 1990,
The new Olympic stadium was inaugurated and blessed by Pope John Paul II before hosting the first World Cup match between Italy and Austria.
Today,
The second largest sports venue in the country is home to both clubs of the capital,
AS Roma and Lazio of Rome.
If in Rome,
The venue is located away from the city centre in a large sports complex.
in Bilbao,
Sadmames Stadium has always been located in the very heart of the Basque city.
bordered by small mountains.
The first stadium, nicknamed the cathedral of football, was built in 1913.
From the 1950s onwards,
It gradually expanded by adding stands all around it.
The stadium will be completely transformed in just two years of work and inaugurated in 2013.
It is located in the same place as the previous one.
Because for the fervent supporters of Athletic Bilbao,
It was unthinkable not to do it.
to move the new stadium to the outskirts.
This veritable institution,
ambassador of a territory and a people,
had to stay in the city centre.
This is Caesar Ascarate,
Spanish architect,
who was tasked with designing the new stadium.
The tradition of fans coming to this place for over 120 years,
We couldn't change it.
And to find other alternatives for moving the stadium out of the city,
The club itself and the supporters prevented it.
Located along the river,
the Ria,
The stadium is a key architectural element of the city.
It follows in the tradition of landmark monuments.
The town hall dates from the 19th century,
the Guggenheim Museum, built in 1997 by Frank Gehry,
the Euskalduna Congress and Music Palace,
and the Iberdrola tower, covered in glass and 165 meters high.
The most renowned architects participated in the transformation of Bilbao.
This former industrial city has reinvented itself to become one of the most attractive cities in Spain.
Located in the heart of the city,
The site is easily accessible and served by public transport.
Pedestrians,
them,
they take Licencia de Oposa street.
The stadium is in a very important location in the city.
right in front of Licenciado Posa street.
This classic and legendary street in Bilbao,
because from there you have an unobstructed view of the stadium.
And this is where the fans arrive on match days.
It's almost like a pilgrimage to the football stadium.
This passionate man had to be brimming with inventiveness to integrate the arena as seamlessly as possible into the urban landscape.
He then divided the facade into five rings of identical height.
similar to the floors of a typical downtown building.
He then decorated it with patterns resembling boat sails.
This shape is repeated 2500 times and we have distributed it over 5 floors.
In this way,
This allows for a building on a human scale and in harmony with the other buildings in the city.
But with its 55,000 seats,
The new stadium also had to meet the challenge of being larger,
taller and more impressive than the old one,
without encroaching further on the city.
As you can see,
He is quite well integrated into the city.
both in height and size.
You know,
Football stadiums are generally the largest monuments in cities in terms of size and volume.
We therefore had to reduce its footprint so that it occupies as little space as possible and reduce its height to the maximum.
So that it is at the same level as the city's buildings.
To achieve this,
We had the ground buried approximately 8 meters below street level, which reduced the height of the stadium.
The new Sad Mames stadium is one of the most compact stadiums in the world.
If the architect has succeeded in integrating the structure into the urban fabric,
The manufacturers still faced a double challenge.
How to go from a stadium with a capacity of 43,000 to 53,000 spectators while staying in the same location?
But also how to build the new structure,
before even destroying the old one,
and while the team continues to play its home games.
The challenge was to successfully build the wall between the river and the river.
The old stadium,
a hotel and the city's university.
Oscar Malot,
today, stadium director
followed the project at the time as an engineer.
The construction of the stadium was very tightly controlled because the plot of land is very small.
And above all,
The old stadium was to continue operating while the new one was being built.
The maneuvers of each element and each machine that we used during construction were very limited.
And the challenge is all the greater because this future football temple must be built while respecting the neighborhood located just a few meters away.
Since the stadium is in the city,
We needed to limit our noise pollution.
We have a hotel next door.
relatively close neighbors.
So at night,
Of course,
It was necessary to prioritize the least noisy tasks so that the neighbors could sleep.
So yes,
This limited our room for maneuver and we really had to intensify the work during the daytime hours.
In total,
That's more than 15 machines.
4 cranes,
some of which reach 150 meters in height,
who worked on the site for months and removed more than 33,000 tons of rubble.
A colossal construction project in the heart of the city.
The dimensions of the new stadium,
designed by the architects,
were 236 meters long by 191 meters wide.
But the space between the riverside roads and the old stadium was only 156 meters.
From May 2010,
Only the first three-quarters of the stadium were built on the available space.
without touching the old stadium,
which continued to host the club's matches.
During the summer of 2013,
The old stadium has been demolished.
The deadline was 22 months for the first stage.
That's a very short time for building a stadium.
And the biggest challenge was demolishing the street that separated the old stadium from the new one.
Of course,
the stands of the old stadium,
whose arch was the emblem of the old Saint-Mames.
At that moment,
We only had three months to do this demolition and gain the 10 meters of turf that the new stadium needed to reach the regulation dimensions.
That's where things got tricky.
because if we don't meet the deadlines,
We ended up without the old stadium and without the new one.
After the lawn was laid out,
The last quarter of the stands was able to be built during the 2013-2014 season.
while the club was playing its matches in its new stadium,
still under construction.
While the construction of the San Mames stadium was a race against time,
The same is true for another legendary football venue,
the Olympic Stadium in Rome.
To host the 1990 FIFA World Cup and meet the standards of international organizations,
The stadium in the Italian capital must be destroyed.
then rebuilt in barely two years.
A record time.
When the FIFA representatives came to see the progress of the work,
They wanted to take the World Cup away from us.
because they said it was impossible to build the stadium in such a short time.
And indeed,
The workers call it the Stadium of Miracles.
Because we encountered difficulties in building this stadium in less than two years.
It was necessary to demolish and build a new stadium.
And it was a true miracle.
The lack of space and the narrowness of the construction site were a problem.
There were 50 cranes on the construction site at the same time.
50 cranes that had to be moved to transport the equipment.
and assemble this enormous construction set.
But to facilitate this colossal undertaking and build the stadium in less than 24 months,
The roof is detached from the rest of the building.
The Italian National Olympic Committee is designing the project.
The roof structure must cover all the stands.
but so as not to obstruct the spectators' view,
It is necessary to avoid using a load-bearing structure inside the stadium.
The weight of the roof is then supported by a whole structure of beams and cables located above the roof and supported by 8 gigantic columns at the 4 corners of the stadium.
The reinforced concrete towers can reach over 70 meters in height and the main roof structure is between 45 and 55 meters high.
The entire roof structure represents more than a third of the size of the stadium.
Constrained by time,
The task facing the builders is immense.
Especially since an unexpected event is about to occur.
One month after the start of the work,
The project is suspended.
This imposing roof is rejected by the Ministry of Cultural Heritage and the Environment and by the Administrative Court of Rome.
The eight towers, each over 50 meters tall, have too great an impact on the landscape.
For manufacturers...
It's a real blow.
We have to start all over again from scratch.
We found ourselves with a blank page 16 months before the inauguration.
The height of the columns was the main problem.
We needed to find the lowest possible solution.
Everything had to be redone.
the project and the entire construction.
The challenge was already immense.
But now it is a real feat that architects and engineers must accomplish hand in hand.
This roof needs to be as low as possible and quick to build.
It was ultimately the architect Massimo Maggiovichi who found the solution.
Build a roof using a bicycle wheel.
That's when I came up with this new idea.
which had never been achieved in such a large stadium.
That is to say, the idea of ​​a bicycle wheel that is completely independent of the rest.
It doesn't need to be supported by large structures like these tall towers.
Actually,
Everything is contained within this ring.
which can actually be very low.
Because this structural concept allows it.
This revolutionary idea,
first conceived in a stadium,
is immediately validated by the authorities.
The roof structure resembles a bicycle wheel.
The center of the roof,
the inner ring,
is made up of 12 steel cables almost 9 cm in diameter.
They represent the center of the bicycle wheel.
80 junctions help to reinforce the inner ring.
From these junctions extend the steel cable lattices which are comparable to the radius of the bicycle road.
Each lattice consists of a top cable and a bottom cable.
They are connected to each other by vertical cables for added stability and support.
Each trellis is attached to what could be considered the rim.
a peripheral anchoring structure.
This structure is made up of steel tubes about twelve meters high.
The entire structure is connected to the outer ring, which is supported by 16 columns which,
to support the weight,
must be extremely robust.
To minimize the weight supported by these 16 columns,
The choice of membrane is crucial.
The ideal combination?
A fiberglass layer that forms the resistant part of the membrane,
covered with a polytetrafluoroethylene film,
a type of plastic that guarantees the impermeability and protection of the fiberglass.
The engineers have accomplished a remarkable feat.
To create a sophisticated roof,
light and low in less than 16 months.
This race against time earned it the nickname Stadium of Miracles.
Today,
30 years later,
I wonder how I found the courage to propose this solution, which had never been implemented before.
I must admit that at that moment,
We lacked the knowledge to guarantee a perfect result.
Actually,
We trusted our intuition.
But as we know,
We must always push the boundaries of technology.
It is therefore the imagination and audacity of this man that made it possible to achieve this architectural feat and to make this roof a global reference.
The other major innovation of the Olympic stadium,
It's an extension of the TV stand.
It owes its name to the river.
the Tiber,
which crosses Rome and passes close to the city walls.
During the massive construction work of 1990,
The TV stand is the only part of the stadium that has been preserved.
The rest of the enclosure,
constructed primarily with low-quality cement,
was completely destroyed.
The Tévéré stand was left and reinforced because it is a testament to the old stadium.
The walls between Avertin and the fountains can still be seen.
Travertine was used as a symbol.
We left it as is and just enlarged the upper wooden section.
Like that,
We can still admire the symbols of the continuity of the stadium's history.
SO,
even if we redid everything,
We have thus preserved a historical record of the TV stand.
The Tévéré stand was therefore extended by 16 additional rows to accommodate the 70,000 spectators in the stadium.
The engineers therefore had to innovate to increase the height of the grandstand while minimizing the weight borne by the existing structure.
Jaime Manca,
architect and specialist in wooden stadiums,
takes us to the foot of the grandstand.
Here is the Tevere stand,
produced in 1990 for the World Cup.
Above this reinforced concrete pillar structure,
We created a structure using laminated wood.
This lightweight structure supports inclined beams which in turn support the aluminium bleachers.
All of this makes it possible to have an ultra-lightweight system.
It is a material that weighs 500 kg per cubic meter.
It is therefore significantly lighter than any other material.
Reinforced concrete,
him,
weighs 2500 kg per cubic meter.
Steel,
more than 6000.
Its extreme lightness makes it a very easy material to use.
It allows for a very simple site setup and quick assembly.
We fit together parallel epipedals,
It's a bit like assembling a giant Lego set.
Laminated wood is made by assembling boards coated with melamine glue and pressed together.
So,
after 12 hours,
This results in a beam known as a gloulam beam.
These wooden beams and these wood seeds are wooden beams.
The aluminum cheapskates are the symbol of the expansion of the TV-style grandstand.
But doesn't wood present a major risk?
That of catching fire and bursting into flames very quickly.
Glulam is flammable because it is a wood-based material.
but it is a wood that catches fire very slowly.
It reduces its carbon layer by 6 tenths of a millimeter per minute.
Knowing this allows for predefined evacuation delay times.
which would be impossible if other materials were used.
For example,
in case of high temperature,
Steel has a tendency to collapse.
At 800 degrees,
It loses all its mechanical characteristics and collapses.
Firefighters are therefore more likely to authorize a building made of gloulam rather than steel or reinforced concrete.
Using gloulam,
Rome's Olympic Stadium delivered a great performance.
To build a new, extremely lightweight grandstand on top of an existing structure,
and this,
in record construction time.
Stadium builders continue to demonstrate inventiveness and push their limits.
This was the case of Massimo Maggiovichi,
who created the bicycle wheel roof for the Olympic Stadium in Rome.
A revolutionary concept that gives it this very distinctive appearance.
But in the Basque city,
The architect of the San Mames stadium had to face a new challenge.
At the end of the work,
The enclosure is covered by a roof that protects the stands from the rain.
But the city is subject to regular bad weather and after a few months of use,
Athletic Bilbao finds that the roof of the new stadium does not adequately protect the pitch and the lower part of the stands.
Architects are then faced with a new challenge.
Carrying out a roof extension while the construction work is finished.
It was a really big engineering challenge because there is nothing similar in the world.
A 50-meter-long metal structure that supports an extension
Who,
they,
They measure between 18 and 23 meters in length, depending on the area.
and all held together by taut cables.
The existing cover,
with a cantilever of 50 meters,
It was not designed to support additional weight.
The extension must therefore be as lightweight as possible.
The architects immediately considered the most suitable solution,
the roof made of a bicycle wheel.
First of all,
a new steel tube structure is fixed to the edge of the old structure.
It allows for the accommodation of a system of cables stretched between tubes which together form a complete oval-shaped structure.
On top of this are positioned inclined metal frames onto which plastic film is placed.
The whole thing is then inflated and allows rainwater to be collected at the junction between the two parts of the roof.
In the end,
The extension is 14.92 m at the shortest width and up to 23 m in the curves.
We worked to create a very lightweight cover.
simply made from steel cables connected to the existing roof using reinforcements.
Together,
They form a structure commonly referred to as the bicycle wheel system.
This extension is therefore designed as if it were a bicycle wheel, with the cables representing the spokes of the wheel.
We were able to give it this shape and integrate it harmoniously into the architecture of the rest of the stadium.
To make matters worse,
The bicycle wheel roof structure functions as a single unit.
which requires extremely meticulous installation.
Especially since the work had to be completed in less than 4 months.
during the summer league break.
To achieve this feat,
The architects used an extremely lightweight roofing material.
Ethylene,
tetrafluoroethylene
said ETFE.
Philippe Lennert is the head of Vector Foil Tech,
the only company in the world to have made ETFs its core business.
He reveals to us the manufacturing secrets of this material used in the greatest contemporary architectural projects.
In this part of the design office,
We define all the information intended for the production of the TFE panels.
So all the people you see here are working on the smallest details of the design of the TFE panels.
For example...
How to cut the leaves?
How do I weld them together?
This is where it all begins.
They are then transferred to production where we weld together the different sheets of TFE to obtain a complete panel.
The TFE is composed of resin,
small granules that are melted and then transformed into a flexible film.
When the designers have finished their project,
The workshop takes over and carries out the first step,
cutting the material.
It is on these large automated tables that the ETF film is carefully cut into the desired shapes.
The second production step consists of welding the TFE sheets together.
Here,
The single sheets of TFE that we cut from the roll are assembled and welded into a continuous layer.
And then on these large tables,
The layers are placed one on top of the other to create the TFE cushions.
While Vector Foil Tech has complete mastery of the ETF production chain,
each new major project,
like that of a stadium,
constitutes a real challenge.
Stadium projects are generally our biggest projects.
The whole process can really take a lot of time and use a lot of manpower.
In many cases,
We work 24 hours a day.
7 days a week,
with 3 teams to create a 20,000-seat stadium,
30,000 or 40,000 m2,
which represents a huge amount of manufacturing.
Such was the challenge for the roof of the San Manes stadium.
which is made up of 20,000 m2 of inflatable plastic cushions.
The facade of the enclosure,
also composed of ETFE,
is equipped with a lighting system which,
on match nights,
gives the stadium its full splendor.
Today,
If this material is used in the world's largest architectural projects,
That's because it offers many advantages.
The major advantage of ETFE compared to glass,
It's lightness.
For example,
A final year project panel
It's 1 to 5%
the weight of a glass panel,
which represents a significant saving in the coating material.
And that also means you don't need such a large framework.
What's interesting about the TFE,
It's because it's the chemical counterpart of Teflon.
that you may know with the frying pan.
And it has a very important characteristic,
the non-stick characteristic.
With the TFE,
This means that dirt doesn't really stick to the outside of the panels.
Our clients don't have to spend a lot of time or money on exterior cleaning,
because the rain takes care of it for them.
UV resistant,
It does not discolor or degrade.
Translucent,
It lets through a large amount of light which naturally nourishes the grass.
So with ETFE,
You are building a transparent or translucent building envelope for the long term.
And not just something that will last 10 or 15 years and then need to be replaced.
If within the San Mames stadium,
We only play football.
the Olympic Stadium in Rome,
him,
It accommodates many other disciplines.
In total,
More than 60 sporting events take place on the pitch each year.
Lawns are under increasing strain.
which therefore needs to be ever more resilient.
Francesco Rossini,
agricultural engineer,
specialist in sports turf,
works at the University of Viterbo.
Depending on the sport,
Each type of grass has technical specifications that must be respected for the game to be perfect.
SO,
THE...
The characteristics of a stadium pitch must be different from those of a golf course or polo field or even a tennis pitch.
Each sport has its specific characteristics that the pitch must respect.
And in order for Rome's grass to withstand such activity,
Francesco conducted laboratory tests to find the best formula.
We focused on optimizing the turf at the Olympic stadium.
And we found solutions so that it could be used for both football and rugby.
And that's thanks to our recent research.
While most stadiums use artificial turf,
that of Rome,
him,
opted for a natural lawn capable of withstanding impacts,
but also to the Mediterranean climate.
A custom-designed lawn that combines two complementary grass species,
the fat bermuda shorts and the English ryegrass.
This combination of cultures designed in the United States,
in Florida and California,
It was adopted for our Mediterranean climate.
in order to make the ground more resistant.
Indeed,
if we didn't have this type of lawn,
we would not be able to host the 64 to 67 events that take place on average each year in the stadium.
This composition provides all the necessary characteristics of torsional strength and soil hardness.
It meets UEFA's criteria and as you can see,
The root ball is extremely robust.
but just enough so that football and rugby players can play there safely.
With this system composed solely of natural species,
We guarantee the same services and performance as a synthetic lawn.
The thick bermuda shorts withstand high temperatures and create the solid mesh of the grassy carpet.
With its density and ultra-fast growth,
It is the most popular type of turf for sports fields.
The second type of grass is perennial ryegrass.
It is cold-resistant and withstands foot traffic very well.
These seeds are sown on the grassy bermuda shorts,
then covered.
covered with earth,
compacted and watered.
The grass mat is 4 cm thick.
It rests on a 4 cm layer of silica sand.
Sand is composed of more than 180 different minerals.
It dries very quickly and ensures water drainage.
which maintains the quality of the grass.
Beneath the sand is a 15 cm layer of volcanic soil.
These small pebbles have many beneficial properties.
It facilitates drainage.
help reduce weed growth,
They protect the roots from frost in winter and retain freshness in summer.
All of this rests on one meter of soil.
While the collaboration between the University of Viterbo and the Olympic Stadium has been a success in terms of the quality of the pitch,
It also helps to protect the environment.
We are trying to improve the quality of the turf,
but also to protect the environment,
by reducing the use of pesticides and fertilizers,
and especially by optimizing the use of heating and lighting,
which have a high energy cost.
Rome's Olympic Stadium has gone to great lengths to ensure that its natural grass makes this arena one of the most beautiful playing venues on the planet.
In the cathedral of football at San Mames,
Football is a religion that transcends all generations and social classes.
On match nights,
The entire San Mames district is in turmoil.
The supporters, in a procession, walk up the main avenue to the stadium before invading the esplanade.
For manufacturers,
It was essential to preserve this very special fervor,
renowned throughout the world.
This was the main challenge we had to overcome when designing the stadium.
We needed to build a modern stadium.
a larger stadium
but we absolutely did not want to lose all the atmosphere that the old one had.
The stadium,
located in the heart of the city center,
it had to occupy as little space as possible.
And surprisingly,
It is this factor that has allowed the mythical atmosphere of this cathedral of football to be preserved.
To reduce its height,
the stadium was initially buried 8 meters below the surface.
The stands,
them,
were built as close as possible to the ground.
And above all,
They were tilted at the steepest angle permitted by international football authorities.
To preserve the atmosphere of the old San Mamés,
We also decided to slope the roof downwards.
with all the beams of the metal structure pointing towards the center of the field.
The acoustic pressure from the spectators therefore reverberates under the roof and travels onto the playing field.
And the final factor that helps to achieve this atmosphere is to give homogeneity to all things.
All the stands,
to the entire audience,
this red ambiance with all these seats,
the white of the roof,
the green of the lawn,
All of this amplifies the unique atmosphere of football, which is experienced in a special way.
as was the case in the old San Mames and now here.
And on the ground,
The players also feel this legendary atmosphere.
I was fortunate enough to be the last captain of the old stadium and the first captain of the new one.
In the old Saint-Mames,
As soon as you climbed the steps and saw the field,
It reeked of football.
No ?
NOW,
in the new one,
when everyone sings,
Everyone stand up,
when the team traps the opposing team in the penalty area...
Oh dear,
That's great!
I mean,
The atmosphere in the stadium is deafening.
And the players notice it.
because their hair stands on end.
And it's one of the most beautiful moments I've ever experienced.
The atmosphere is incredible.
The stadium is much more symmetrical than the old one.
It is much more compact and people are closer to the grass.
With all that,
The atmosphere at the matches is incredible.
In Rome,
The two clubs in the capital can also count on their supporters to make the arena vibrate and their chants resonate all the way to the Vatican.
Rome's Olympic Stadium and Bilbao's San Mames Stadium have successfully achieved the incredible feat of reinventing themselves in record time.
and this,
using cutting-edge technologies.
Having become veritable institutions,
Their fame extends far beyond national borders.
attracting viewers from all over the world.